If you're working as an IT system engineer or an IT system administrator, security will
be one of your big upgrades consigned at your company.
Definitely, you want to make sure that all your company devices are properly secured, not
only with fire firewall, windows defender, anti-virus protection, but also making sure that
the device is properly equipped, I want to base with totally equipped device is Bitlocker.
So if you're not actually configured Bitlocking an enterprise environment, you will not
want to be going from individual devices to just configure Bitlocking and save the password
to your local device.
You definitely want to make sure that the password of that Bitlocking is saved to your active
directory or to your Azure Active Directory.
So I'm going to be showing you in this video how to configure this is actually going
to, this is going to be configured in a lab environment, so I'll be showing you how to
configure Bitlocking in an enterprise environment for your, if you're actually doing
this lab environment, or if you're trying to alter to this, the production environment,
you can't only use this video as a guide.
So first of all, you want to actually install the Bitlocker rules on your Windows server,
which allows you to view the Bitlocker key on that device from Active Directory and also
allows you to see the Bitlocker key of that device when something goes wrong with that
device.
So first of all, let's try to add the Bitlocker features.
So I'll just go to click Nest and then select the right, operating system, the right
Windows server that you'll be installing the Bitlocker features.
Let's just click Nest and it's not going to be a role, it's going to be a future, so
we're going to click Nest.
So here, if I hear you can see, we have the Bitlocker driver encryption, that already
been installed.
And then when we scroll down, yeah, we scroll down on other remote server tools.
Yeah, then if I go here to future administrator, you can see we have the Bitlocker driver
encryption, which is good, you're going to select this and then install the features.
So by starting the features, you will now restart your device.
Then I'll tell you that your device, that is not all.
We now need to actually configure a group policy.
So what you need to do is you're going to start a group policy.
And first of all, what we want to actually do, because you want to store the password
in Active Directory, you can see this is the Bitlocker recovery information in Active Directory
domain.
So you double click on that and you enable it.
And there we can.
So it says, okay, require Bitlocker, Bitlocker backup to Active Directory domain service and
the recovery password and the key packages, you can actually select the recovery password
only.
So let me cancel that.
And then now, we now also have some options, for example, you can see we have fixed drive,
data drives, or previous system drives, or removable data drives, but I want to go to the
operating system drives.
And on the operating system drive, here you can see we have required additional authentication
as touch-up.
You want to try to configure that, you can see it's going to say, I'm a lot bitlocker,
with tactical portable TPM, of course required a password or a startup key on a USB flash drive.
So because I'm using a virtual machine for this training, I want to totally configure
this if not, I'm going to receive an error message.
And here you can see it says configure, configure TPM startup, you want to say allow, and
the startup TPM startup and pin, we're going to also allow startup pin with TPM, and also
the startup key, we're going to allow startup key with TPM.
And then lastly, it's going to say, choose how Bitlocker protection, and protect the
operating system drives can be recovered, we're going to say, well, we're going in a
window that has totally recovery password and key passwords as well, so actually the battery,
and here we can see it says allow the 48-digit recovery password, and allow the true for
5 to 5-6 bit recovery key.
So let me just cancel that.
So after you've done this configuration, and then you apply the policy, let me just close
this.
There right now, you can see that this policy has been applied to the long-done position.
Now you need to have one computer, there is a Windows 11 device, so now let's go to
our Windows 11 device, and then you can see this is our seat drive.
So if I decide to click on the seat drive and turn on Bitlocker, remind you, you still need
to turn if you are installing that device for the first time, you still need to turn on
a bit Locker.
So here you can see, I have to choose how Bitlocker, or you want to unlock your driver's
touch-up, so I definitely want to use a pin, I'm going to just go for, let me just enter
the pin, go to my password, and then I'm going to click Nest.
This is a clip, I'm using the taskbase only, or a clip entire disk, I'm going to encrypt
the user taskbase only, I'm going to click Nest, and then you ask a clip show mode, I
will select that and click Nest, and then run the Bitlocker system, check, I'm just going
to click Continue, so it's trying to actually encrypt my device.
So right now, is going to try, I'm going to restart my device, and then the encryption
will continue, and then we can now check and see how our Bitlocker is actually saved.
So let me just restart my device, or I'll actually start later, but definitely I want
to restart my device now.
So now, we need to enter a password to itali, and get access to our device, so I'll just
need to enter my password, the hit enter, and right now you can see that I'm able to
itali, assess my device, we'll go with how my password, I'm not able to get into my
device, and if you try to type the password several times, definitely you'll be requested
to enter a recovery key.
So let's just wait for this device to get started, and then we can now log on to our
device, here we go, if I go now to my file explorer, and I go to this PC, here you can
see that Bitlocker has been configured on this device.
So next I will show you how to itali, recovery key for Bitlocker in case you enter your
PIN code, and something goes wrong, or if you got your PIN code, definitely you will
requested to profile your Bitlocker recovery key.
So let me just show you how to get your recovery key.